# **Joshua Marcus**

**Toolchain Specialist** 

joshmarcus85@gmail.com +13472050416 El Paso, TX, 79930, USA

Experienced, confident and versatile engineer with a background in Systems Engineering, Software Development, DevOps, System Administration and all IT fields. Comfortable and effective in any environment. Experience in healthcare, government and other highly regulated environments. The ideal liaison between development and infrastructure.

## **Work Experience**

## Senior Systems Engineer - Unified Endpoint Management

Mar 2024 - Present

Marriott | Bethesda, MD

- Administer Microsoft Intune in a hybrid environment
- Engineer authentication solutions
- Write and maintain applications to automate processes in Python, Bash, PowerShell and more
- · Write and maintain applications to automate processes in Python, Bash, PowerShell and more
- Responsible for account management lifecycle
- Maintain a high level of user experience and user satisfaction in speed to troubleshoot issues
- Responsible for engineering across the entire CIAM stack
- Required to maintain a high level of professionalism in customer-facing applications
- Committed to providing the best internal user experience possible
- Leverage Graph API and the WorkspaceOne API on a daily basis to automate workflows
- Utilize a test driven development and unit testing strategy

### **Toolchain Specialist**

Jan 2024 - Present

Raytheon | GAMA

- Administer all aspects of cloud infrastructure for AWS, Microsoft Azure and Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
- · Administer Version Control Systems such as Gitlab and Github
- Build wide variety of software using Docker and other tools
- Implement and track infrastructure using Terraform/Cloudformation
- Scripting in Bash, Powershell, Python, Javascript/Typescript and more
- Deploy multi-account environment in AWS using LZA
- Manage and optimize the computer science tooling throughout the program
- Configured Terraform to implement networking between GCP and AWS
- Design and implement Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery
- · Assist with AWS network configurations and network operations
- Configure and maintain cross-platform identity management across Azure, GCP, and AWS
- Utilize a wide base of technical skills and cloud engineering methods on a daily basis
- Utilize Agile methodologies

# Senior Systems Engineer/ Platform Engineer Talkiatry

Jul 2021 - Apr 2024

- Write and debug applications in Typescript, Python, Bash, and more
- Configure and monitor CI/CD pipelines using CircleCI, GitHub, Azure CI/CD (Azure DevOps)
- Design and configure Terraform modules and managed system configurations through modularized Infrastructure as Code strategy
- Utilized deep knowledge of computer science tools to administer AWS and Azure/Enterprise Microsoft services
- Account management for entire lifecycle of a user's presence
- Responsible for all aspects of Identity Access Management and SSO using Microsoft Azure Active Directory (Entra ID),
  OKTA, and other systems
- · Administered and wrote applications interfacing with Snowflake, AWS RDS, Postgres and other databases
- Assisted with implementation and initial onboarding for a Ruby on

- Use container management software such as Docker and AWS ECS
- Leverage automation tools such as Power Automate, AWS Batch and more
- Designed onboarding scripts and process for employee onboarding
- Previously served as Manager of IT Services for a team of six responsible for wide base of system operations
- Utilize Agile methodologies
- Interact with multiple database technologies on a daily basis
- Ensure database security
- Write and assist with SQL gueries for applications and one-off pulls of data
- Management information systems for a team of System Administrators
- Manage access methods for a huge variety of SaaS applications using SSO tooling
- Responsible for all aspects of PaaS

### **Core Skills**

SSO, Authentication, Azure AD, Microsoft Entra, GCP, OKTA, Python, Typescript / Javascript, Linux / Bash, AWS, Azure, Terraform, CI/CD (CircleCI / GitHub Actions), Git, Jira, Powershell, Management, Microsoft Windows, Flexibility, Focus, Intelligence, Potential

### **Education**

William Paterson University

May 2022

Master of Music

**Eastern Illinois University** 

May 2010

**Bachelor of Music** 

#### **Certificates**

CompTIA Security+

CompTIA A+

CompTIA

**Azure Fundamentals** 

Microsoft